Guide to the Louise Seaman Bechtel Papers, 1877-1980 (bulk 1913-1980)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES I. AUTHOR/ILLUSTRATOR/PUBLISHER FILES
  - CREIGHTON, Beatrice
    - Correspondence (Folder 18.221)
  - CROSS, Wilbur
    - Correspondence, 1923-1931 (Folder 18.222)
    - Correspondence including a letter from Helen McAfee re: WC, 1942-1946, 1923 (Folder 18.223)
    - Thanksgiving proclamation, 1961 (Folder 18.224)
    - Article about, also notes by LSB on WC, 1966, n.d. (Folder 18.225)
  - DALGLIESH, Alice
    - Correspondence, 1931-1933 (Folder 18.226)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1970 (Folder 18.227)
    - Correspondence (Folder 18.228)
    - Christmas cards, 1963, n.d. (Folder 18.229)
    - Booklists, n.d. (Folder 18.230)
    - Articles by, 1940-1966, n.d. (Folder 18.231)
    - Articles about, 1972-1979 (Folder 18.232)
    - Photographs, n.d. (Folder 18.233)
  - DAUGHERTY, James
    - Christmas card and Drawing (Folder 18.234)
  - DE LA MARE, Walter
    - Correspondence - letter to Francesco Bianco that LSB has copied in her own hand, ca. 1919 (Folder 19.235)
    - Correspondence about WDLM, 1929 (Folder 19.236)
    - LSB's notes on WDLM, n.d (Folder 19.237)
    - Article by, n.d. (Folder 19.238)
    - Articles about, 1956-1957 (Folder 19.239)
    - Articles about, n.d. (Folder 19.240)
  - DODD, Marion
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Folder 19.241)
  - DOLGOFF, Shirley
    - Correspondence, 1966 (Folder 19.242)
  - DONOVAN, John
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Folder 19.243)
  - DUVOISIN, Roger and Louise
    - Correspondence, 1964-1978 (Folder 19.244)
    - Christmas cards, ca. 1950-1965 (Folder 19.245)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 19.246)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 19.247)
    - Articles by, n.d. (Folder 19.248)
    - Articles about, 1952, n.d. (Folder 19.249)
  - EAGER, Edward
    - Correspondence, notes, article, 1956, 1964, n.d. (Folder 19.250)
  - EATON, Anne Thaxter
    - Correspondence, 1934-1946 (Folder 19.251)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Folder 19.252)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1964 (Folder 19.253)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1969, n.d. (Folder 19.254)
    - Christmas cards, 1932-1949 (Folder 20.255)
    - Christmas cards, 1950-1957 (Folder 20.256)
    - Christmas cards, 1953-1964 (Folder 20.257)
    - Christmas cards, 1965-1970 (Folder 20.258)
    - Copy of poem sent to LSB and "Children's Book Week Card,", 1965, n.d. (Folder 20.259)
    - Publishing info and and typescript of speech about AE, 1963, 1941 (Folder 20.260)
    - Articles by, 1934-1940 (Folder 20.261)
    - Articles by, 1942-1948 (Folder 20.262)
    - Articles about, 1946-1971 (Folder 20.263)
  - EDEY, Marion
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 20.264)
  - EICHENBERG, Fritz [See also Series VI for artwork of Eichenberg.]
    - Correspondence, 15 March 1949 (Folder 20.265)
    - Christmas cards, 1933-1961, n.d. (Folder 20.266)
    - Articles by, 1943-1964 (Folder 20.267)
    - Scrap w/ FE's return address stamp, n.d. (Folder 20.268)
  - ERICKSON, Phoebe
    - Correspondence, 1951-1957 (Folder 20.269)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 20.270)
    - Articles about, 1954, n.d. (Folder 20.271)
    - William Allen White Children's Book Award Voting List and Bookmark Photos, 1957 (Folder 20.272)
    - Photos, 1957 (Folder 20.273)
  - EVANS, Herbert and Dorothy
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 21.274)
  - FARRAR, John
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Folder 21.275)
  - FENNIMORE, Stephen
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Folder 21.276)
  - FIELD, Carolyn
    - Correspondence, 1954 (Folder 21.277)
  - FIELD, Rachel
    - Correspondence with notes by LSB, 1931-1932 (Folder 21.278)
    - Correspondence with notes by LSB, 1934-1939 (Folder 21.279)
    - Correspondence with notes by LSB, 1939-1942 (Folder 21.280)
    - Christmas carol and birthday card (Folder 21.281)
    - Correspondence about Re from her mother, Lucy Field, 1942-1943 (Folder 21.282)
    - Correspondence about RF from Arthur Field (husband), 1942 (Folder 21.283)
    - Correspondence about RF from Madeline Field, 1975 (Folder 21.284)
    - Correspondence about RF from Ruth Feis, 1963-1964 (Folder 21.285)
    - Correspondence about RF from Gladys English and Althea Warren, with note by LSB, 1946-1951, 1946-1958 (Folder 21.286)
    - Correspondence about RF from Bertha Mahony Miller, 1942 (Folder 21.287)
    - Correspondence about RF from Prentiss Taylor and original draft of LSB's letter to the Curator of the Yale University Library re: RF's collection, 1956, n.d. (Folder 21.288)
    - LSB's notes on Rachel Field, n.d. (Folder 21.289)
    - Published poem and articles by RF, 1970, 1932 (Folder 21.290)
    - The Horn Book - The Rachel Field issue - with Memorial Flyer, July-Aug 1942 (Folder 22.291)
    - Typescript of LSB's Article about RF in The Horn Book, 1942 (Folder 22.292)
    - Typewritten copy of article about RF, 1934 (Folder 22.293)
    - Anouncement of RF exhibition, 1956 (Folder 22.294)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 1 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.295)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 2 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.296)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 3 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.297)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 4 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.298)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 5 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.299)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 6 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.300)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 7 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.301)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 8 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.302)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 9 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.303)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 10 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.304)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 11 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.305)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 12 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.306)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 13 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.307)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 14 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.308)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 15 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.309)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 16 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.310)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 17 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.311)
    - Scrapbook by LSB, folder 18 of 18, n.d. (Folder 22.312)
  - FISH, Helen Dean
    - Correspondence (Folder 23.313)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 23.314)
    - Articles about, n.d. (Folder 23.315)
  - FOLMSBEE, Beulah
    - Correspondence, 1958 (Folder 23.316)
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 23.317)
  - GANSER, Helen
    - Correspondence, Jan-Nov 1961 (Folder 23.318)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Folder 23.319)
    - Correspondence with enclosure, 1973 (Folder 23.320)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Folder 23.321)
    - Material pertaining to the dedication of the Helen Ganser Library, 1968 (Folder 23.322)
    - Photos, ca. 1964-1968 (Folder 23.323)
  - GARNETT, Eve
    - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Folder 23.324)
  - GODDEN, Rumer
    - Correspondence (Folder 23.325)
    - Christmas cards, 1949-1952 (Folder 23.326)
    - Articles by, 1956, n.d. (Folder 23.327)
    - Articles about publicity, 1963, n.d. (Folder 23.328)
    - Cosmopolitan Club program announcing speech by RG, also, misc. article in files of LSB, n.d. (Folder 23.329)
  - HANDFORTH, Thomas [See also Series VI for artwork by Handforth.]
    - Correspondence, 1940-1946 (Folder 23.330)
    - Christmas Cards, 1936-1940, n.d. (Folder 23.331)
    - Articles by, 1939 (Folder 23.332)
    - Horn Book news sheet featuring posters of TH's book Mei Li, clipping of drawing by TH, and exhibition announcement, 1939, 1940, 1971 (Folder 23.333)
  - HASTINGS, Marguerite
    - Correspondence, ca. 1974-1975 (Folder 24.334)
    - Articles about, 1975, n.d. (Folder 24.335)
    - Programs and announcements for concerts, 1970-1974 (Folder 24.336)
    - Programs and announcements for concerts, 1975 (Folder 24.337)
    - Programs and announcements for concerts (Folder 24.338)
    - Programs and announcements for concerts, 1975, n.d. (Folder 24.339)
  - HENDERSON, Brooks
    - Correspondence, ca. 1928-1931 (Folder 24.340)
    - Correspondence, 1932-1938 (Folder 24.341)
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 24.342)
    - Correspondence about BH from Hugel Jackson, 1940 (Folder 24.343)
    - Poem by BH, drawing of BH, n.d. (Folder 24.344)
    - LSB's notes, LSB's copy of letter, n.d. (Folder 24.345)
  - HIRSCHMAN, Susan
    - Correspondence, 1965-1976 (Folder 24.346)
    - Correspondence (Folder 24.347)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 24.348)
    - Articles about, 1974-1975 (Folder 24.349)
  - HODGES, Margaret
    - Correspondence, 1978 (Folder 24.350)
  - HODGSON, Ralph and Aurelia
    - Correspondence with note by LSB, 1942-1968 (Folder 25.351)
    - Christmas cards, 1943, n.d. (Folder 25.352)
    - Note and nursery rhyme (Folder 25.353)
    - Correspondence and tribute - book of poems to celebrate RH's 100th Birthday, 1971 (Folder 25.354)
    - "The Flying Scroll," parts 1 and 4-11, a poem by RH, 1944-1951 (Folder 25.355)
    - Memorial card, Choral Festival announcement, 1962, 1968 (Folder 25.356)
  - HOFFMAN, Malvina
    - Correspondence, 1927-1950 (Folder 25.357)
    - Correspondence, 1950-1952 (Folder 25.358)
    - Correspondence re: MH's bronze stallion, 1951 (Folder 25.359)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 25.360)
    - LSB's notes, n.d. (Folder 25.361)
    - Articles about, catalogue page, 1937, 1953, 1964, n.d. (Folder 25.362)
    - Photos of sculpture, other photos and one article, 1932, ca. 1953, n.d. (Folder 25.363)
  - HORN BOOK [Correspondents include: Siri Andrews, Elizabeth Dyer, Beulah Folmsbee, Jeanne Jarmon, Jennie Lindquist, Mary Manthorne, Bertha Mahony Miller, Anne Robinson, Eulalie Ross, Thomas Todd, Ruth Viguers]
    - Correspondence, 1934-1958 (Folder 26.364)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Folder 26.365)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Folder 26.366)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Folder 26.367)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Folder 26.368)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1974, n.d. (Folder 26.369)
  - IVINS, William Mills, Jr.
    - Correspondence, 1944-1960 (Folder 27.370)
    - LSB's notes, n.d. (Folder 27.371)
    - Article about, 1963 (Folder 27.372)
    - Photo, 1956 (Folder 27.373)
  - JOHNSON, Helena Chase
    - Christmas cards, 1962, n.d. (Folder 27.374)
  - KELLY, Eric
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Folder 27.375)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 27.376)
    - Correspondence about the Trumpeter of Krakow from and to Susan Hirschman- included are the color proof to the Trumpeter jacket and reviews about the book sent by LSB, 1966 (Folder 27.377)
    - Correspondence about the Trumpeter of Krakow from Beth Caples - includes copy of letter from LSB and a 1958 review (Folder 27.378)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence about Trumpeter of Krakow - Richard Kelly, Andrzej Klominck, Olga Malkowska, 1972, 1966, n.d. (Folder 27.379)
    - Materials and articles and publication information directly about Trumpeter, 1928-1970 (Folder 27.380)
    - Prints of chapter markers for Trumpeter, n.d. (Folder 27.381)
    - Photos of EK and Trumpet loaned by Krakow for exhibit (Folder 27.382)
  - KETCHUM, Arthur
    - Christmas cards, 1942-1943, n.d. (Folder 27.383)
    - Poem from Edwin Bechtel on AK's anniversary of is ordination, 1939 (Folder 27.384)
    - Sermon by, 1948 (Folder 27.385)
    - Notes by LSB, n.d. (Folder 27.386)
  - KNOPF, Alfred
    - Correspondence, 1956-1960 (Folder 27.387)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 27.388)
    - Articles about, 1962-1974 (Folder 27.389)
  - LANGER, Susanne K.
    - Correspondence, 1957, n.d. (Folder 28.390)
    - Article about, 1968 (Folder 28.391)
  - LAPIDES, Linda
    - Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Folder 28.392)
  - LATHROP, Dorothy [See also Series VI for artwork by Lathrop.]
    - Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Folder 28.393)
    - Correspondence, 1934-1957 (Folder 28.394)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1962 (Folder 28.395)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1970 (Folder 28.396)
    - Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Folder 28.397)
    - Correspondence (Folder 28.398)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 28.399)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 28.400)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 28.401)
    - Articles by - including her Caldecott Medal Acceptance, 1931-1938 (Folder 28.402)
    - Articles about, 1938 (Folder 28.403)
    - Articles with reference to DL, 1938 (Folder 28.404)
    - Exhibition announcements - with invitation and articles, 1966, 1963, 1975 (Folder 29.405)
    - LSB's notes on DL and Hitty (Folder 29.406)
    - Misc. items including library book list (with Hitty) bibliography of DL and publishing info., 1929, 1969, 1964 (Folder 29.407)
    - Horn Book calendar, selected illus. by DL, 1972 (Folder 29.408)
    - Photographs of DL, her dogs and Hitty (Folder 29.409)
  - LEIGHTON, Clare [See also Series VI for artwork by Leighton.]
    - Correspondence, 1934-1970, n.d. (Folder 29.410)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 29.411)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 29.412)
    - Advertisement for the Woodcut Society featuring CL, 1939 (Folder 29.413)
  - LENSKI, Lois
    - Correspondence (Folder 29.414)
    - Christmas card, ca. 1920s (Folder 29.415)
    - Article by, 1948 (Folder 29.416)
    - Articles about Univ. of Southern Miss., 1953, n.d. (Folder 29.417)
    - Special Children's Collection Medallion booklet - LL winner, 1969 (Folder 29.418)
    - Advertisement featuring LL Gift package, 1962 (Folder 29.419)
  - LINKLATER, Eric
    - Correspondence (Folder 30.420)
  - MCCLOSKEY, Robert
    - Correspondence from RM's wife, 1964-1975 (Folder 30.421)
    - Caldecott award acceptance, 1958 (Folder 30.422)
    - Articles about, 1943-1969, n.d. (Folder 30.423)
    - Film portrait announcement, n.d. (Folder 30.424)
    - Photos, 1952, n.d. (Folder 30.425)
  - MACKINSTRY, Elizabeth [See also Series VI for artwork by MacKinstry.]
    - Correspondence, 1934, n.d. (Folder 30.426)
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 30.427)
    - A Fairy Calendar for EM and Article, 1963, n.d. (Folder 30.428)
  - MANNIS, Effie Lee
    - Correspondence, 1953 (Folder 30.429)
  - MANTHORNE, Mary [ See Also Horn Book Correspondence]
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 30.430)
  - MASEFIELD, John
    - Correspondence, 1953-1958, n.d. (Folder 30.431)
    - Christmas cards, 1945-1958 (Folder 30.432)
    - Christmas cards, 1960-1966 (Folder 30.433)
    - Correspondence about JM, 1961 (Folder 30.434)
    - Articles about, 1955-1969 (Folder 30.435)
    - Photo, drawing (printed) of JM by Henry Lamb, 1916, 1961 (Folder 30.436)
  - MEIGS, Cornelia
    - Correspondence, fragment, 1929-1953, n.d. (Folder 31.437)
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 31.438)
    - Article by, 1928 (Folder 31.439)
    - Articles about, including one written by LSB, 1932-1972, n.d. (Folder 31.440)
    - LSB's notes and some by CM (Folder 31.441)
    - Photos, ca. 1930, n.d. (Folder 31.442)
  - MELCHER, Frederic
    - Correspondence, 1929-1952 (Folder 31.443)
    - Christmas cards, 1938-1964 (Folder 31.444)
    - Correspondence about FM, 1963 (Folder 31.445)
    - Article by, 1950 (Folder 31.446)
    - Articles about, 1940-1963, n.d. (Folder 31.447)
    - FM Scholarship Fund Auction Directory, 1956 (Folder 31.448)
  - MEYER, Agnes and Eugene
    - Correspondence from Agnes, 1949-1964, n.d. (Folder 31.449)
    - Correspondence from Eugene, 1951-1955 (Folder 31.450)
    - Correspondence from Katherine Meyer Graham, 1963 (Folder 31.451)
    - Articles about Meyer family, 1956-1961, n.d. (Folder 31.452)
    - Commencement speech by EM at Stanford University, 1951 (Folder 31.453)
    - LSB's notes, n.d. (Folder 31.454)
  - MILLER, Bertha Mahony [See also Horn Book Correspondence.]
    - Correspondence, 1931-1933 (Folder 32.455)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1963 (Folder 32.456)
    - Christmas card, ca. 1923 (Folder 32.457)
    - Articles by, 1928-1943 (Folder 32.458)
    - Articles about - also LSB's notes about, n.d. (Folder 32.459)
    - Correspondence and material related to the establishment of the BMM Seminar Room at the School of Library Science at USC, 1974 (Folder 32.460)
    - Correspondence and material related to BMM's winning of the ninth regina Medal, awarded by the Catholic Library Association, 1967 (Folder 32.461)
  - MITCHELL, Lucy Sprague
    - Correspondence, 1934-1957 (Folder 32.462)
    - Articles by, 1934 (Folder 32.463)
    - Articles by, 1935 (Folder 32.464)
    - Articles by, 1955 (Folder 32.465)
    - Articles about, 1967 (Folder 32.466)
    - "Notes from Bank Street,", 1953-1957 (Folder 32.467)
  - MOORE, Anne Carroll
    - Correspondence, 1927-1946 (Folder 32.468)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1955 (Folder 32.469)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Folder 32.470)
    - Correspondence (Folder 32.471)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 33.472)
    - Correspondence from LSB (Folder 33.473)
    - Correspondence from Frances Clarke Sayers regarding ACM, including Christmas card, 1952-1970 (Folder 33.474)
    - Correspondence from LSB to FCS re: ACM, 1961, n.d. (Folder 33.475)
    - Notes by LSB on ACM (Folder 33.476)
    - Material relating to ACM's winning of the Regina Medal from Catholic Library Association, 1960 (Folder 33.477)
    - Article about, 1939 (Folder 33.478)
    - Articles about, 1941-1961 (Folder 33.479)
    - Photos, 1942 (Folder 33.480)
  - MOORE, Marianne
    - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Folder 33.481)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1956 (Folder 33.482)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1960 (Folder 33.483)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1969, n.d. (Folder 33.484)
    - Published speech - The Gazette of The Grolier Club, 1949 (Folder 33.485)
    - Articles by, 1959-1967 (Folder 33.486)
    - Articles about, 1950-1962 (Folder 33.487)
    - Articles about, 1962-1966 (Folder 33.488)
    - Articles about, 1966-1973 (Folder 33.489)
    - Articles about, n.d. (Folder 34.490)
    - Loan Exhibition Program: Skidmore College featuring MM - includes notes used by Ned Bechtel for a speech he gave them, 1950 (Folder 34.491)
    - Poem published in The New Yorker, 1962 (Folder 34.492)
    - Invitation to The Grolier Club MM's speech, 1948 (Folder 34.493)
    - Christmas card to MM, n.d. (Folder 34.494)
    - LSB's notes, n.d. (Folder 34.495)
    - Advertisement featuring MM, n.d. (Folder 34.496)
  - MUNARI, Monroe
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 34.497)
  - MUNN, Ralph
    - Correspondence with (enclosures), 1953 (Folder 34.498)
  - NARAMORE, Elizabeth
    - Correspondence (Folder 34.499)
    - Copy of book review, 1951 (Folder 34.500)
  - NERMAN, Einar
    - Correspondence and photograph (Folder 34.501)
  - PAGET-FREDERICKS, Baron Joseph [See also Folder 1000 for Program for "Song of the Troubadour," by San Francisco Players Guild, Inc., designed by JP-F, 1959.]
    - Correspondence (Folder 34.502)
    - Correspondence (Folder 34.503)
    - Correspondence (Folder 34.504)
    - Correspondence including letter from JP-F copied in LSB's hand (Folder 34.505)
    - Correspondence about JP-F, 1963 (Folder 34.506)
    - Gallery Exhibition Notice, n.d. (Folder 34.507)
    - Articles about, 1953- 1963 (Folder 34.508)
  - PARRISH, Anne
    - Correspondence, 1932-1944 (Folder 35.509)
    - Correspondence, 1944-1946 (Folder 35.510)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1956 (Folder 35.511)
    - Christmas cards, 1932-1951 (Folder 35.512)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 35.513)
    - Postcards, 1937-1949 (Folder 35.514)
    - Correspondence from AP to Margaret King, 1922 (Folder 35.515)
    - Correspondence from Dillwyn Parrish, 1922-1923 (Folder 35.516)
    - Correspondence about AP from Robert Kaudy, 1950 (Folder 35.517)
    - LSB's notes, n.d. (Folder 35.518)
    - Articles by, 1949 (Folder 35.519)
    - Articles about, 1957-1960 (Folder 35.520)
    - Portion of book jacket, n.d. (Folder 35.521)
    - Photos and drawings (Folder 35.522)
  - PETERSHAM, Maud and Mishka
    - Christmas cards, 1933, n.d. (Folder 35.523)
  - PORITZ, Lily
    - Correspondence, 1964 (Folder 35.524)
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 35.525)
  - RACKHAM, Arthur
    - Exhibit notice, article, 1967, 1960 (Folder 35.526)
  - RENICK, Marion
    - Correspondence (Folder 35.527)
  - RICHARDS, George
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 36.528)
  - RILEY, Elizabeth
    - Correspondence, 1955-1961 (Folder 36.529)
    - Christmas card, 1972 (Folder 36.530)
  - ROBINSON, Mabel Louise
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Folder 36.531)
    - Copy of book review, 1951 (Folder 36.532)
  - ROGINSKI, Jim
    - Correspondence, Aug-Nov 1974 (Folder 36.533)
  - ROSS, Eulalie
    - Correspondence, Jan-Dec 1970 (Folder 36.534)
  - RYMER, Alta
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Folder 36.535)
  - SANFORD, Eva Matthews
    - Christmas cards, 1932-1952, n.d. (Folder 36.536)
    - Article about, n. d. (Folder 36.537)
  - SAYERS, Francis Clarke - (see MOORE, Anne Carroll)
  - SCHEEL, Eugene
    - Correspondence and materials about Margaret Wise Brown, 1968 (Folder 36.538)
  - SEIGNOBOSC, Françoise
    - Correspondence, Apr-June 1951 (Folder 36.539)
    - Cards, n.d. (Folder 36.540)
    - Article by, n.d. (Folder 36.541)
    - Drawings, n.d. (Folder 36.542)
  - SEWELL, Helen [See also Series VI for artwork of Sewell.]
    - Correspondence, 1953-1957 (Folder 36.543)
    - Correspondence (Folder 36.544)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 36.545)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 36.546)
    - Correspondence about HS from Claude Bailey, Apr-Aug 1957 (Folder 37.547)
    - Correspondence about HS from Claude Bailey, 1957-1958 (Folder 37.548)
    - Correspondence (with photograph) from Claude Bailey, 1958 (Folder 37.549)
    - Correspondence about HS from Claude Bailey, 1958-1962 (Folder 37.550)
    - Correspondence about HS from Claude Bailey, July-Oct 1962 (Folder 37.551)
    - Materials written by HS's Claude Bailey, 1960-1963 (Folder 37.552)
    - Memorial materials for Claude Bailey's wife, Emily and article about Uncle Claude, 1959, 1962, n.d. (Folder 37.553)
    - Materials from Claude Bailey, n.d. (Folder 37.554)
    - Correspondence from HS's niece, Pat Hill, 1957-1963 (Folder 37.555)
    - Christmas cards from HS's niece, Pat Hill, 1958-1975 (Folder 37.556)
    - Correspondence about HS from Henry Pitz, June-Nov 1957 (Folder 37.557)
    - Correspondence to LSB on the article she wrote for theHorn Book on HS - includes letters from Eunice Blake, Ruth Gagliardo, October- November 1957, n.d. (Folder 37.558)
    - Correspondence to LSB on the article she wrote for the Horn Book on HS includes letters from Maude Crowley, Fritz Eichenberg, Oct-Nov 1957, n.d. (Folder 37.559)
    - Correspondence from Maria Cimino, Assoc. Librarian of the NY Public Library regarding HS and an exhibition of her work, 1957-1959 (Folder 37.560)
    - Correspondence from Jennie Lindquist re: HS - includes excerpts from letters on LSB's Sewell article, 1957, n.d. (Folder 37.561)
    - Misc. letters to LSB re: HS, 1957 (Folder 37.562)
    - 2 misc. letters - one to HS, the other to Yetta Arenstein which quotes a letter to HS, 1951, 1957 (Folder 37.563)
    - Articles about, 1957-1960, n.d. (Folder 38.564)
    - The monthly letter of the Limited Editions, Club, featuring HS, 1940-1957 (Folder 38.565)
    - Published speech which makes reference to HS, 1946 (Folder 38.566)
    - Invitation and announcement for HS exhibit - NY Public Library, 1959 (Folder 38.567)
    - Copy of drawing used as frontis-piece for LSB's article in the Horn Book, ca. 1934 (Folder 38.568)
    - Book jacket cover of Problems of Art - illustrations by HS, n.d. (Folder 38.569)
    - Publishing advertisements for books illustrated by HC, 1948, 1963, n.d. (Folder 38.570)
    - LSB's notes for Horn Book article on HS, n.d. (Folder 38.571)
    - LSB's notes, n.d. (Folder 38.572)
    - Programs for presentation of memorial windows for Emily Moore Bailey, HS's aunt, and for Helen Moore Sewell, 1958, n.d. (Folder 38.573)
    - Photographs of HS memorial window in Calvary Episcopal Church, Burnt Hills, NY (Folder 38.574)
    - Photographs of HS and of HS's niece, 1920, 1946, 1929, 1931 (Folder 38.575)
  - SHRIFTE, Evelyn
    - Correspondence, 1953 (Folder 38.576)
  - SIMON, John Allsebrook